Guide to the Doris Duke Audiovisual Collection, 1919-2012 and undated RL.10005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Audio, 1923-1989
  - Audiocassettes, 1974-1989; 48 items
    - BB King, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0009_01_pm.wav; RL10005CS0009_02_pm.wav)
      Presumably a live recording of a BB King Concert. Location and date unknown.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0009)
    - Herbert Pickard, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0010_01_pm.wav)
      Presumably a short tape made by gospel singer Herbert Pickard for Doris Duke. At beginning of tape he says, "Hi this is Herbie, I'm going to play whatever comes to mind in the next 10-15 minutes." Includes three songs including one in which he wrote ("Together Again").
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0010)
    - Terry Cole-Whittaker / Nathalie Prettyman, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0011_01_pm.wav; RL10005CS0011_02_pm.wav)
      Reverend Terry Cole-Whittaker speaking about holistic health. Presumably a copy of a live recording.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0011)
    - Use [?] Lord, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0012_01_pm.wav)
      Cassette tape consists of only one gospel song. Unknown singer accompanied by piano. Sounds like a live recording, although poor quality.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0012)
    - Copyright Jack Daugherty, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0013_01_pm.wav; RL10005CS0013_02_pm.wav)
      Consists of a variety songs sung by unknown male and female singers. Also includes saxaphone instrumentals. Possibly the album "Romance" produced by Jack Daugherty.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0013)
    - Unknown, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0014_01_pm.wav; RL10005CS0014_02_pm.wav)
      Tape begins with short audio clip of Brewster senate hearing from 1947. This leads into a telephone interview with Howard Hughes (from the Paradise Islands in the Bahamas) conducted in the early 1970s. Reporter ends by asking the listeners to decide for themselves is authentic or not. Side 2 is James McNamara recounding the 1947 inagural flight of the Spruce Goose. This is followed by with the live audio of the flight recorded in 1947.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0014)
    - Unknown, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0015_01_pm.wav; RL10005CS0015_02_pm.wav)
      Sounds like a recording of a radio broadcast. Unknown man recounts the assination of John F. Kennedy and then speaks about his theories (including Zionism and occultism) which lead to the assination of the President.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0015)
    - Unknown, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0016_01_pm.wav; RL10005CS0016_02_pm.wav)
      Two unknown men having what appears to be a casual conversation about the Hunza people. One man is asking the questions and the other man talks about his experience visiting remote people/villages.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0016)
    - Unknown, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0017_01_pm.wav; RL10005CS0017_02_pm.wav)
      Unknown woman speaking about Atlantis and alien people visiting earth. Other people ask her questions and refer to her as "master".
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0017)
    - Master: Syncavier 50% 100% no noise and lexicon, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0019_01_PM.wav)
      Recorded only on half of Side 1. Man announces different variations of Syncavier (50%, 100%), no noise and lexicon for two Nat King Cole songs, Unforgettable and For Sentimental Reasons, and then plays the songs at the various speeds.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0019)
    - Luis Arcaraz and the Jonah Jones Quartet, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0021_01_PM.wav; RL10005CS0021_02_PM.wav)
      Contains 49 tracks. Sounds like a recording of a commercial album.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0021)
    - He Touched Me / I Need the Lord, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0023_01_pm.wav; RL10005CS0023_02_pm.wav)
      Live recording of unknown woman singing an assortment of gospel songs accompanied by piano.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0023)
    - Ray Charles, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0024_01_pm.wav; RL10005CS0024_02_pm.wav)
      Live recording of Ray Charles, most likely at the Newport Jazz Festival.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0024)
    - Cleveland Choir Church, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0025_01_PM.wav)
      Live recording of Cleveland Choir Church. Includes both solo performances and group performances. Recorded on Side A only.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0025)
    - Unknown, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0027_01_pm.wav)
      Unknown woman singing gospel music accompanied by piano. Sounds like a live recording. Recorded on Side 1 only.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0027)
    - Dorothy Norward and High Point Choir. LL and High Point Choir., undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0029_01_pm.wav)
      Live recording presumably of Dorothy Norward and High Point Choir. Includes both solo and group performances and audience clapping and participating in songs. Recorded on Side 1 only.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0029)
    - LL at Newpoint, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0030_01_PM.wav; RL10005CS0030_02_PM.wav)
      Live recording of what appears to be a choir practice session. Choir performs several gospel songs, but most of recordings are piano only. Recorded on Side 1 only.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0030)
    - Hugh Shannon, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0032_01_pm.wav; RL10005CS0032_02_pm.wav)
      Live recording of Hugh Shannon singing jazz standards at unknown club. During introduction to one song he mentions "my beautiful friend Doris Duke who is here tonight."
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0032)
    - Unknown, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0034_01_pm.wav)
      Sounds like a recording of a commercial album. Artist unknown. Recorded on Side 1 only.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0034)
    - Meadowland's Concert, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0035_01_pm.wav)
      Live recording of various gospel groups and soloist, including Pilgrims Jubilee, Albertina Walker, and Inez Andrews. Recorded on Side 1 only.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0035)
    - Les Aivi Mamao, undated
      Hawaiian music.
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0036)
    - LL Newpoint Choir, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0039_01_pm.wav; RL10005CS0039_02_pm.wav)
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0039)
    - Untitled recording, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0040_01_pm.wav; RL10005CS0040_02_pm.wav)
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0040)
    - The Tantra Way, by Norbu Chen, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0041_01_pm.wav; RL10005CS0041_02_pm.wav)
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0041)
    - LL + Yvette, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0044_01_pm.wav; RL10005CS0044_02_pm.wav)
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0044)
    - LL + Choir, undated (Digital-materials SET-0006, Audio-file RL10005CS0042_01_pm.wav)
      - Original audiocassette (Box 35, Audio-cassette RL10005-CS-0042)
- Sheet Music and Index Cards, 1899-1949 and undated; 640 items
  This series primarily consists of commercial sheet music, composition books, lyrics handwritten by Doris Duke, and index cards listing the phonodiscs she owned.
  - Jacket for The Jazz Scene, which is part of a set of 6 albums. The phonodiscs are located in the Phonodisc subseries, circa 1949 (Box 26)
  - Embossed portfolio containing sheet music and composition books for the harp. Several of the music sheets include handwritten notes by Doris Duke, 1923-1924 (Box 27)
  - Song Classics by the Best Composers for Soprano, 1899 (Box 27)
  - Various lyrics handwritten by Doris Duke, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Sheet music handwritten by Doris Duke (1 of 5), undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Sheet music handwritten by Doris Duke (2 of 5), undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Sheet music handwritten by Doris Duke (3 of 5), undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Sheet music handwritten by Doris Duke (4 of 5), undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Sheet music handwritten by Doris Duke (5 of 5), undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Commercial sheet music - "A" (1 of 2), undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Commercial sheet music - "A" (2 of 2), undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Commercial sheet music - "B" (1 of 2), undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Commercial sheet music - "B" (2 of 2), undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Commercial sheet music - "C", undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Commercial sheet music - "D", undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Commercial sheet music - "E" and "F", undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Commercial sheet music - "G", undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Commercial sheet music - "H", undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Commercial sheet music - "I" (1 of 3), undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Commercial sheet music - "I" (2 of 3), undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Commercial sheet music - "I" (3 of 3), undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Commercial sheet music - "J" and "K", undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Commercial sheet music - "L", undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Commercial sheet music - "M" and "N", undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Commercial sheet music - "O", "P", and "R", undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Commercial sheet music - "S" (1 of 2), undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Commercial sheet music - "S" (2 of 2), undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Commercial sheet music - "T" (1 of 4), undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Commercial sheet music - "T" (2 of 4), undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Commercial sheet music - "T" (3 of 4), undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Commercial sheet music - "T" (4 of 4), undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Commercial sheet music - "U", "V", and "W", undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Commercial sheet music - "Y" and "Z", undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Slides containing damaged frames removed from various films, undated (Box 32)
  - Index cards listing vinyl recordings owned by Doris Duke. Includes categories: Miscellaneous Orchestras, Hawaiian, and Hungarian, undated (Box 33)
  - Index cards listing vinyl recordings owned by Doris Duke. Includes categories: Artists, Duke Ellington, Fats Waller, Rumba-Tangos-Sambas, undated (Box 34)